Guide to the Student Activism Reference Collection, 1934-ongoing UA.01.11.0061
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Student Activism Reference collection
1934-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. University Archives
UA.01.11.0061
1.5 Linear Feet
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Student Activism Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Collection Overview
The Student Activism Reference Collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research. Collection contains materials pertaining to student movements and protests at Duke University. Materials present include flyers, clippings, publications, petitions, chants and slogans, and other printed material. Major topics include: civil rights; human rights; the Vietnam War; and corporate divestiture in South Africa. Materials in the collection date from 1934 and are ongoing.
Collection Arrangement
Collection is arranged in chronological order
Related Material
Allen Building Takeover collection, 1969-2002.
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke Vigil collection, 1968-1988.
University Archives, Duke University.
Ron Grunwald papers, 1973-1980.
University Archives, Duke University.
WDBS collection, 1949-1983.
University Archives, Duke University.
Civil rights movements -- North Carolina; College students -- Political activity -- United States; Corporate divestiture -- South Africa; Human Rights; Student movements -- North Carolina; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements; Duke University -- Students -- Political activity
- Student Activism at Duke University, General (Box 1)
- Student Activism, Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Student Rebellion, 1934 (Box 1)
- Duke bus strike, 1949 (Box 1)
- Civil rights demonstrations, 1960- (Box 1)
- Cotton Bowl Petition 1961 (Box 1)
- Project Nicaragua, 1962-1973 (Box 1)
- The Real World, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
- Italian Relief Fund, 1966 (Box 1)
- FBI on campus, 1967 (Box 1)
- 1968 ban on "Disruptive Picketing" (Box 1)
- Vigil, April 1968 (Box 1)
- Allen Building Takeover, 1969 (Box 1)
- Free Academic Senate, 1969 (Box 1)
- The Protean Radish, Independent Radical Weekly of the Carolinas, 1969 (Box 2)
- Vietnam War, 1966-1976 and undated (3 folders) (Box 2)
- Chronicle Coverage [The Vigil] 1968- (Box 2)
- Pickets, Protests & Demonstrations Policy, 1968 (Box 2)
- Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC), 1968-1969 (Box 2)
- ROTC, 1969- (Box 2)
- Students in Politics, 1970 (Box 2)
- Impeachment Rally, Pres. Nixon. 1973 (Box 2)
- Progressive Worker, 1973 (Box 2)
- Movement for Shared Authority, 1975 (Box 2)
- Duke Undergraduate Faculty Coalition on the East-West Expressway, [1978] (Box 2)
- Anti-Draft Rally, March 1980 (Box 3)
- OxFam-America, November 1980 (Box 3)
- Protest "Klan-Nazi" Verdict, Nov. 1980 (Box 3)
- BarbEast (newsletter), 1981 (Box 3)
- Inter-view (newsletter), 1982-1984 (Box 3)
- South Africa, 1984 (Box 3)
- South Africa, Spring 1985 (Box 3)
- South Africa, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
- Take Back the Night marches, 1987-1992 (Box 3)
- Black Faculty Hiring 1988 (Box 3)
- Tiananmen Square, May-June 1989 (Box 3)
- ServiceMaster & housekeepers, 1989 (Box 3)
- Kuwait, 1990-1991 (Box 3)
- Holocaust, 1991 (Box 3)
- Habitat for Humanity, Duke Chapter, 1992- (Box 3)
- NATO bombing of Chinese Embassy in Belgrade, 1999 (Box 3)
- Sweatshop Protests, 2000 (Box 3)
- War on Iraq, 2002 (Box 3)
- Duke Organizing, 2006 (Box 3)
- 2008 (Box 3)
- Duke Students and Workers in Solidarity Occupation of Allen Building, 2016 (Box 3)
- The People's State of the University, 2018 (Box 3)